we got so scared and psyched out we
spanked ourselves but my dad would spank
that was the ultimate punishment he
would spank I truly wish with my whole
heart I had grown up in a world like
today where parents use timeout I I
would have loved timeout
that's how parents get tough with their
kids today you know what mister you
pushed me to the edge I'm not taking any
more time that's right you push Johnny's
head into the brick wall and got blood
everywhere
[Applause]
you're not getting away with that mm-hmm
that's right mister you can just grab
your cell phone computer games and head
to your room I would have loved timeout
if I had timeout I would have started on
my day by just walking up to my brothers
yeah why don't you touch me now I'll
take the timeout but my dad would spank
not only would he spank he would send us
to his bedroom where you had to wait to
be spanked spanking in him by itself is
bad enough but to have to wait to be
spanked look at me side section we had
to wait to be spanked you had time to
look at every belt he owned it was like
each belt was talking I hope he picks me
one time my dad sent my brother Kyle and
I to his bedroom at the same time to
wait to be spanked it's bad enough when
you're by yourself but when you're with
another brother and you can see the pain
and fear in his eyes and he's saying
stupid stuff like this is gonna hurt
isn't it yeah it's gonna hurt shut up
we got so scared and psyched out we
spanked ourselves we just went walking
right by our dad where are you going we
already took care of it but when you
have that many kids you have to be good
at discipline my dad was he was a genius
at discipline let me give you an example
at one time when there were only seven
of us we lived in a small house we had
one bedroom for all those kids we had
three bunk beds in that bedroom the
youngest child rotated so when our
parents would send us to bed at night
they did not expect immediate quiet you
know you'd be in your bed someone would
start talking you talk back pretty soon
everyone's talking you're in your bed
talking someone might touch you you go
to touch them back except it's dark you
get the wrong guy know everyone's
touching everyone then you're in your
bed thinking wait a minute someone
touched me I bet you there's someone out
there in the dark right now doing the
almost touch and your gamble
[Laughter]
so what I've been talking touching it in
as and ankles on you get creative you
come up with ideas say I wonder if I
could jump from the top of this bunk in
the dark to the top of that bunk and you
try it and you make it and then you tell
your youngest brother sure I think you
can make it too and he hits hard but the
point is there's a lot of commotion
talking touching and jumping my dad
didn't handle it like a lot of other
parents he didn't yell out idle threats
like you better stop don't make me come
down there I'll give you one more chance
he didn't do that here's on my dad
handled it we'd be talking touching
jumping suddenly the bedroom light would
be on and he was just there we did not
know how he got there when that bedroom
light came on all he saw was seven heads
pop up we look like a bunch of prairie
dogs looking for an eagle
we're all looking at him thinking things
like why doesn't he make noise why do we
have a ninja dad and he'd make eye
contact with each and every one of us
and when he made eye contact you would
just look down I remember looking down
and thinking oh please don't pick me to
kill he did this one by one toe we were
all looking down the next thing we know
our bedroom light is out except now
we're all thinking I'm pretty sure he's
still in here
you wanna Sun came up that's a position
you were in I got a I gotta ask you this
we're first before we talk about
anything else you ever have one of those
moments where you realize how other
people see you I had this happen in an
airport I had a connecting flight I had
been up since 3:30 in the morning so I'm
dead tired dead tired walking on a
middle of the airport terminal dead
tired head down debt and care head down
didn't care and that beep beep cart was
behind me you know that beep beep beep
beep beep cart you know that cart that
transports people to their gate when
they get there they can magically walk
that cars behind me beep beep beep beep
I thought you know what you'll get there
when I'm good and ready for you to get
there finally we reached the point where
the car could pass me and as the Kart
fasted me an elderly lady on the card
says you would think with those ears
that he could hear us
[Applause]
why are you groaning I don't get that
that makes no sense at all
not before before we keep going could
you do me a favor would you just unfold
your arms that's negative body language
and I don't like it just did you hear
yeah you should have done that without
me looking over there no it's just
that's a hard lap position that's just
not a good lap position and no I I have
to tell you this I came straight here
from Miami I had a direct flight from
Miami I just had I just got off a cruise
ship well maybe not a direct flight I
don't think that's possible to Provo is
it can you get a direct flight because
you got an airport I saw that I flew
into the wrong Airport I flew into Salt
Lake City and apparently I could have
flown right into Provo is that is that
possible can you find have you do you
know you have an airport but no I just I
got to tell you it's just nice to be
here
get got off a cruise ship and now I'm
here and it's just like people are
you're dressed like there could be a
blizzard and you're gonna survive and
then I've been watching you from up
there and some of you you don't even
take your coats off you just you this
has been what pushing two hours and you
leave that thing on
I'm I'm if I had to guess I would guess
you work at the post office that's what
I would guess cuz you got you left your
jacket on and you got a little nervous
twitch going on take it off
[Laughter]
don't don't cover your mouth when you
laugh just let the laugh out this is a
comedy show if he tries to stop you
leave it alone I mean it I mean
that when I say I'm glad to be here you
know what I'm gonna I'm marking you if
you laugh I know I'm having a great show
don't you can look away but when you
look back I'll still be looking at ya
you just sit there with that stoic look
on your face and that tonight look at me
when I talk to you no I mean it I'm so
happy to be here I had a you know people
when you work on a cruise ship people
come up to you oh you're lucky you get
to work on cruise ships however for what
I do that's not true all the time this
cruise that I was working on there was
mostly Germans in the audience Germans
in the audience and as we all know the
Germans are a jovial group
this is my impression of a German got
laughing and they weren't really
laughing I finally looked at a guy and
said why are you laughing he said ich
first and it does Niek after the show I
found the International hostess and
asked her what does ich forced on did
that sneak mean she said I do not
understand I said ich first I already
forgot that move up and I gotta tell you
though just talk about travelling just
for a little bit my wife and I we love
Ireland we just we discovered Ireland on
a cruise and then we went back just
because we loved it so much the people
are so friendly the country is just
beautiful but it said Irish accent it
gets us we absolutely love that Irish
accent but every time it would get to be
half past the hour Nancy would just go
oh you're gonna do it again aren't you
and I would go yes soon as it got to be
half past the hour I will look for
anyone I could find just to ask him what
time it was what time is it at 7:30
[Laughter]
how can you not love the turkey and it
gave and it gave me ten minutes to play
731 732 733-6025 33 is simply responded
with wall
[Laughter]
then they went on the topic to look for
it I don't see nothing where is it and
then you and then the British at normal
conversation they make you feel good I
told a British guy I got up at 8 a.m. he
looked at me and said brilliant to which
I responded scusi all right I got a you
know what I gotta be careful because
there's a black tape line here and they
told me not to step over that and I
don't know why but it's dangerous if I
step over that just it's just it won't
be good something went bad will happen
and you'll be safe because you got your
jacket on
you know you'll be out of the building
before everyone else you're a survivor
is what you are
look at you don't care about her you're
just gonna take care of yourself oh yeah
go ahead take your jacket off all right
here's the bonding type question this
should bring us all together does anyone
does anyone here come from a family
seriously you raise your hand usually
people just laugh but you knew you came
from a family I got eight brothers and
one sister I grew up in a family of 10
kids anyone come from a larger family
than that 10 yeah what do you got 14 how
many brothers how many sisters take your
time
what 11 and 3 and then you count
yourself that would be 15 did you did
you hear the question this was 11 and 2
you got two brothers oh three sisters so
you got 10 brothers then well would be
10 because you got 10 brothers 3 sisters
that's 13 and then you is 14 unless you
want to change your answer
I'm glad I can help you out you know
right now you've made this a show I'll
never forget this is the first time
you've figured out the brothers and
sisters in your family it was profile
like they're not good you're still
trying to figure it out okay
all right back me up on this large
family large for a large family you have
to adapt to survive everyone parents
included my dad adapted he learned how
to have fun with us he used to love
taking us to the store you'd only say
one thing spread out they can't watch
all of us
[Laughter]
most kids most kids their favorite
holiday is Christmas not when you're
from a large family because it might not
be your turn to get a present a year a
large family your favorite holiday is
Halloween because it is incentive based
if you hustle you can stock up for the
year Halloween comes around all you know
is you're gonna run for as hard as you
can as long as you can a lot of kids try
to tell you Oh Halloween is at 10 p.m.
wrong Halloween ends when people quit
answering the door and most kids are
just concerned about what they're gonna
be for Halloween you ask a kid from a
large family what are you gonna be I'm
gonna be as fast as I can
you're gonna wear a costume a costume
would slow me down and you hate it when
you get you that nice lady's also a nice
lady that just wants to talk Halloween
night she wants to have a conversation
and what are you supposed to be I do not
have time for this put the candy in the
bag I had one brother he wouldn't even
talk to people Halloween night they
tried to talk to him we just look at him
and go
I've seen grown men just back away just
throw Kenya and maybe he'll lose
[Laughter]
[Applause]
we had a new guy move into the
neighborhood one year he just looked at
my brother and said ask Oozie and you
know what you hate you you know actually
what you love is the lazy guys house the
lazy guy Halloween night the lazy the
guy that puts a bowl full of candy on
his front porch with the note please
take one we don't only dump the bowl we
took the bowl we took the note cuz you
want to show other kids you've got to
read this this is funny and we use
pillowcases because you know those I
mean that pillowcases you can't fill
them up but it doesn't it's physically
impossible we tried every year but you
got the pillowcase and then you see the
kid with the paper bag I'd love to help
you pick up your candy
[Laughter]
but you know what you grew up in a large
family you're more creative you learn
how to have fun or other kids don't
because you don't have as many toys and
stuff and that kind of inspires that
creativity and we did we learned how to
have fun where other kids didn't give
you this example we love Church when we
were growing up loved it church
we loved Church absolutely loved it
Church loved it
Church only place we know that you could
go to sit down and this really happens
they pass a bowl full of money down your
aisle
we didn't even have to say
trick-or-treat for one Sunday my dad
looked and saw what we were doing he
looked like a guy without a microphone
[Music]
it is it shout when you see your dad
doing that you realize he's hope but she
do it comes natural for a kid now I got
a lot of younger brothers and the
younger sister younger brothers and
sisters they're not right there mentally
off they think goofy their whole goal is
to get you to snap and get you in
trouble they will waste an entire day
they will hurt their own body to get you
to snap and get in trouble I had one
younger brother in particular he was
really good at getting under your skin
no matter when you looked at him no
matter when you looked at him all he
would ever do is this
they're not right there mentally off you
ever have a younger brother or a sister
just walk up and touch you they just
want to touch you and you're thinking I
can ignore that but after about an hour
it starts to get to you and just when
you're ready to snap they change weapons
they go from the touch to the almost
touch the almost touch is worse than the
touch they just put it out there till
you pick it up with your vision once you
spot it you can't look at anything but
then they come in for the almost touch
and that's when you snap you try so hard
not to but it's like your arm has a life
of its own whack now my brother is
crying I'm looking around for a stick
hoping someone else hit him at the same
time I don't want to go down for this by
myself he goes running off to our dad
yeah Fred hit me well what'd you do to
him I didn't do nothing
then my dad's from the other room Fred
get in here why'd you hit him well he he
almost touched me and as soon as you see
you know you're in trouble not like your
brothers standing behind my dad
[Laughter]
now everyone everyone would always ask
my parents what was it like raising ten
kids and they always said there was so
many stories that they could choose from
like one time I got together with all my
brothers and we pooled our money and we
ordered a monkey out of the back of a
magazine okay apparently not that
uncommon in Provo I will always remember
the date August 22nd my dad was sitting
on the front porch UPS truck pulled into
the driveway driver got out with the
small box walked up to my dad and said
sir where's the monkey that you ordered
my dad looked at my mom and said Joanne
line him up but this story they said
best epitomized what it was like raising
ten kids was this one my dad was sitting
at the kitchen table we had recently
seen the movie Mary Poppins my dad is
sitting at the kitchen table looking out
the window he sees going by the window
holding an umbrella my brother Jeff and
he hit the ground hard
my dad said if it had ended there he
could understand but then I went by the
window Terrell went by the window and
then Kyle went by the window and he did
not even have an umbrella my dad came
outside and looked at all of us laying
on the ground and he said now when you
three saw your brother Jeff fail the
umbrella did not work why did you still
jump to which I replay what we did we
didn't think he did it right and then
you know how sometimes parents get
sucked into kid logic too much because
then my dad actually yelled at Kyle and
you did not even have an umbrella
- which Kyle snapback yeah like it
helped out
[Applause]
you know I'm gonna walk over here I saw
the what is it a costume shop and they
got the John Wayne placard for the
costumes it's given an exempt bright you
guys see it because when I was a kid my
favorite movies were westerns to this
day there's still westerns but John
Wayne was always number one I can watch
a John Wayne movie a lot of times
afterwards a lot of times afterwards I
get psyched I find myself walking around
like this
you know I know and it feels good it's a
powerful walk and then I started
thinking about it John Wayne was lucky
he's a big man because if you speed up
his watch here's what you've got oh come
here little horsie now you guys like me
you like to eavesdrop I walk into a
restaurant some people sitting at a
table where would you like to sit I want
to sit by them because it's fun
especially eavesdropping on women they
talk about good stuff fun stuff
interesting stuff see guys are always
the same well you know what play they
should have called shut up you work at
McDonald's you don't know women talk
about good stuff you want to know what
he did to me yes first when you yell out
like that then they're gonna know you
were eavesdropping
but it you know it's it's it's funny you
know from my eavesdropping I've come to
the conclusion that we're starting to
worry about way too many things in in
our world some of the things we choose
to worry about might not be quite as
important as as we think and I'll give
you this example I actually I heard this
on a radio PETA the group not to bread
PETA People for the Ethical Treatment of
Animals and we need that organization
because if two squirrels should bump
into each other one really should say
scusi
but Peter they had their spokesperson on
a radio this lady she said they want to
ban fishing
she said fishing is cruel because fish
have the same central nervous system as
people so they feel pain like us she
then went on to say how would you like
it if you were walking down the street
and your lip was impaled in you're
yanked out of this environment into a
different environment where you couldn't
breathe
and I started thinking well that would
mean that you were a fish because people
are way too smarter we should be and if
we're not maybe it's better than we're
gone as if you're walking down the
street with your buddies and you see
some food on a hook walk around it I
think we should be a little bit
suspicious anyway you follow the sudden
out of the blue there's a sandwich
bobbing in front of us
we're worrying about way too many things
sometimes we try so hard to worry we end
up worrying the wrong way I overheard a
couple guys talking about this 940 pound
man first guy goes nine hundred and
forty pounds that is too bad
yes okay goes yeah he almost made it to
a thousand and then I started thinking
about the PETA lady if she was correct
it really was something out there
fishing for humans could you imagine
their surprise if they caught that guy
oh you know he would be mounted and
hanging on a wall that there's your
largemouth big bellied human I caught
him on a turkey spinner you almost
pulled me out of the spaceship
we're worried about way too many extra
things I was eavesdropping I overheard
some people talking about zoos they said
they don't like zoos because they're
cruel to animals there's not enough
space it's not their natural environment
well you know what I disagree I like
watching the wildlife shows you ever
watch the wildlife shows you ever see a
bunch of lions take down a zebra know
people say Oh nature's beautiful shut up
nature's ruthless its vicious it's not
like Disney would have us believe the
animals don't meet in the woods and sing
and dance it's not a musical the zebras
not standing there with a bunch of lions
all over thinking gee it sure is nice to
be contributing to the circle of life
it's hard to watch the lion still hands
grab the zebra by the throat the others
bite in places that aren't nice to bite
til it falls over then they hang out a
stroll tell it suffocates meanwhile the
other lions are looking at each other
like you gonna wait no I'm gonna eat now
you go interview that zebra and ask him
how he feels about zoos cuz I think his
answer might surprise you
I think the zebras in the zoo if they
could talk thank God I'm in the zone the
Lions are right over there and they
can't get to us and you know after a
while the zebras in the zoo would start
to get cocky you know what I think I can
take them I tell you what the next time
you get into the zoo to meet with the
anti zoo person try throwing this I'll
very seldom used in a zoo debate should
be used more often because it's quite
effective some people even say brilliant
after the anti zoo person makes their
point you just look him in the eye and
simply say this the zebras in the zoo
can take a nap you know I thought
everyone would be with me at this point
let me see if I can explain and bring
more people in if you are a zebra and
you can take a nap you are a successful
zebra because if a zebra in Africa were
to say hey I think I'll take a nap the
other zebras okay we'll get you later
all right I'm losing people
alright let me just try this just use
your imaginations go with me and I think
you'll all be with me on the point I'm
trying to make if I were a zebra in
Africa and a zoo truck pulled up no
actually if you're laughing in zoo truck
you got the right idea cuz I got way too
many other people looking at me like
I've never seen a zoo truck if I were a
zebra in Africa and a zoo truck pulled
up I would both from the herd you don't
need a tranquilizer gun don't even put
the ramp down cuz I'm a truck
because I'd like to get some sleep
that's as far as I can go
[Applause]
but at least at least a zebra leaves an
honest life though doesn't it it's an
honest life it knows it has to run for
its life every day compare the life of
the zebra to the plate of the cow the
cow does not know
the cows born on the farm or farmer
takes care of it there's a barn for
shelter they feed it every day if it
gets sick a vet comes out the Col walks
around thinking everybody loves me then
one day the farmer says who wants to go
for a ride
and a cow's thinking why not this is my
impression of a galloping car
[Applause]
now to make it more lifelike for the
people who aren't quite with me move you
ever drive for a really long time you
start to think goofy you see things in a
twisted way ten straight hours I'm
driving this livestock truck passes me I
roll my window down and yell out job
they're gonna kill you I swear one cow's
head snapped up it had been a British
cow
whoa
[Applause]
all right this is my favorite subject
actually I've been married for 35 years
I'm very happy I asked my wife if I was
happy she told me I am that's good
enough for me when I got married I
relationship changed immediately not
gradually but immediately my wife
started to share knowledge with me
knowledge I had no idea she had before
we got married tremendous amounts of
knowledge she must have stored
throughout the years waiting to share
with their future husband not all at one
time gets bits and pieces here and there
on an ongoing basis and at one time I
thought it would end now I know it never
will but the thing is I never know
what's gonna trigger her desire to share
additional knowledge that is a tricky
part that's a part that keeps us on our
toes it could pop up at any time for any
reason or absolutely no reason at all
there are days when I'm gonna walk
through a room and I see my wife oh I
think I'll go the other way
and really haven't memorized yesterday's
lesson yet
we've got a big midterm coming up and
I'd like to do well I never know what's
gonna trigger her desire to share
additional knowledge one day I just
opened our back door that's all I did
simply open the back door look at me
people just opened the back door perhaps
slightly too long I don't know what the
exact time parameter is I only know I
must have went over because my wife or
Alton yelled shut the door you just led
800 mosquitoes into the house now I had
no idea that mosquitoes fly in swarms of
800 I would think that many in a swarm
you'd see something come through the
door I saw nothing but my wife with her
keen eyesight and wealth of knowledge
knew that 800 got into our house god
bless her we could have been bitten to
death that night I got married I no
longer need the Discovery Channel I
guess what I'm trying to say to you is
that marriage can be good because you
learn things that you never knew when
you were single marriage can be good
because you learn things that you never
knew when you were single and you know
what you see examples of that around us
all the time I mean a cafeteria behind
an elderly couple husband reaching for
whole milk reaching for whole milk
listen carefully reaching
for whole milk men reach his wife states
you do not drink whole milk he did not
stop he did not turn to reply just
feared off went straight to the skim
milk I watched this and I thought how
lucky that man was to have followed that
woman how many years did he drink the
wrong milk you learn things when you get
married that you never knew when you
were single for instance now that I'm
married I realized that I never would
have survived had I stayed single if I
hadn't gotten married when I did I
probably would have been dead in a
matter of months I'm being there when I
was single I was wild I lived on the
edge you would not believe some of the
things I used to do for instance when I
was single I used to wear my shoes in
the house
[Laughter]
I'm not making that up I really did I
did not know carpets are supposed to
live thousands of years you learn things
did you get married you never know when
you were single for instance nothing I'm
married I know that I breathe way too
loud my wife not only told me I breathed
her love she told me the exact distance
from which people can hear me my oh I
know what her knowledge is incredible
you learn things when you get married
that you never knew when you were single
for instance now that I'm married I know
when it's time to leave a party
[Laughter]
I never used to know when I was single I
would do really stupid things like stay
until I quit having fun I never realized
they she left hours ago simply because
it was time what come here leaving a
party man it's time pal and you should
get married so you know to
see sometimes sometimes when people
start applauding other people are like
now I don't want to move our arms you
learn things when you get married you
never knew when you were single for
instance now that I'm married I realize
that I never knew how to get dressed you
ever get dressed up to go out with your
wife you come out of the bedroom when
she just looks at you and says no you go
back now I will help you if it's a
British husband whoa you're married long
enough she doesn't have to say anything
you come on that bedroom you see a
certain look you just do a little you
turn you learn things and you get
married you never knew when you were
single you see it around us all the time
today in the hotel I'm staying at very
nice hotel walking down the hallway
behind what had to be a husband and wife
he said I'm hungry she said no you're
not
he walked by me looked up at me as if to
say guess I'm not hungry
sure thought I was hungry sometimes I
get a pain in my stomach like I'm hungry
good thing I married her I could be
eating right now and I'm not even hungry
oh I hope I die first all right I'm
gonna leave this one with you the reason
I saved this one for last is one of my
favorites also one of the more recent
ones you learn things when you get
married you never knew when you were
single I told my wife I want us some
shirts to perform in this is one of the
shirts that she got
and I just said I just told Nancy I
don't want to wear a pink shirt she said
it's not pink it's hibiscus
[Music]
you know what I think I miss school the
day they covered that color don't ever
remember asking another kid hey pass me
that hibiscus crayon and then all my
brothers saw me this shirt neuron making
fun of me yeah he wearing a pink shirt
except now I'm off with new knowledge
it's not pink it's hibiscus and then all
my brothers went
[Music]
and one by one is a got married they got
hibiscus shirts but this is a beautiful
part this is where I know you're with me
honest after a show I had a couple come
up to me the wife wanted her picture
with me and my hibiscus shirt she
started to take her shawl as a joke I
said why don't I wear your shawl her
husband immediately said no the Shah is
salmon that would clash with the
hibiscus
[Applause]
[Music]
you